Guide to the Glenway Wescott Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Research Files, 1924-84; Series VI; 1.68; (4 boxes)
  - MACHADO DE ASSIS, JOAQUIM
    - Clipping, 1954 Jul 26 (Box 394, Folder 3896)
  - MALLARME, STEPHANE
    - Clipping, notes, 1950-1963, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3897)
  - MALRAUX, ANDRE
    - Clippings, 1958, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3898)
  - MANN, HEINRICH
    - Clipping, 1944 Mar (Box 394, Folder 3899)
  - MANN, THOMAS
    - Clippings, 1944, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3900)
  - MATISSE, HENRI
    - Clipping, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3901)
  - MELVILLE, HERMAN
    - Clipping, notes, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3902)
  - MONROE, MARILYN
    - Clippings, notes, 1963-64, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3903)
  - MOORE, GEORGE
    - Clippings, notes, 1932-60, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3904)
  - MOORE, MARIANNE
    - Transcriptions of excerpts of letters from MM, clippings, notes, VOA broadcast transcript, invitation, letter from MW to "Mrs. Josephson", and MM lecture transcript, 1924-81, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3905-3907)
  - MOOREHEAD, ----
    - Clipping, 1952 (Box 394, Folder 3908)
  - NEUMANN, THERESA
    - Clippings, notes, 1954-56, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3909)
  - O'CONNOR, FLANNERY
    - Clipping, 1965 (Box 394, Folder 3910)
  - PERLIN, BERNARD
    - Clipping, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3911)
  - PORTER, KATHERINE ANNE
    - Clippings, 1950, 1972, n.d. (Box 394, Folder 3912)
  - POUND, EZRA
    - Clippings, notes, 1957, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3913)
  - PRITCHETT, V. S.
    - Clippings, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3914)
  - PROUST, MARCEL
    - Clippings, notes, 1950, 1965, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3915)
  - REMARQUE, ERICH MARIA
    - Clipping, 1957 Apr 1 (Box 395, Folder 3916)
  - RILKE, R. M.
    - Clipping, poems, 1957 Apr 18 (Box 395, Folder 3917)
  - RIMBAUD, ARTHUR
    - Clipping, 1954 Dec 23 (Box 395, Folder 3918)
  - RODIN, AUGUSTE
    - Clipping, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3919)
  - ROETHKE, THEODORE
    - Clipping, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3920)
  - ROTHSCHILD, PAULINE DE
    - Clippings, letter, 1971-72, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3921)
  - RUSKIN, JOHN
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3922)
  - RUSSELL, BERTRAND
    - Clippings, notes, 1953-61, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3923)
  - SAINTS
    - Clippings, notes, 1946-58, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3924)
  - SANTAYANA, GEORGE
    - Clippings, 1954, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3925)
  - SARTRE, JEAN PAUL
    - Clippings, 1964, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3926)
  - SIMENON, GEORGES
    - Clippings, note, 1964, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3927)
  - SINGER, ISAAC BASHEVIS
    - Clippings, 1966, 1968, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3928)
  - SITWELL, OSBERT
    - Clippings, notes, 1951-69, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3929)
  - STEINBERG, SAUL
    - Clipping, 1978 (Box 395, Folder 3930)
  - STEVENS, WALLACE
    - [Empty folder], n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3931)
  - TCHELITCHEW, PAVEL
    - Clippings, pencil drawing, copy of letter from Jean Cocteau to Monroe Wheeler, exhibition catalogs and announcements, 1936-55, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3932)
  - THOMAS, DYLAN
    - Clippings, notes, 1952-57, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3933)
  - UPDIKE, JOHN
    - Clippings, 1968, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3934)
  - WHITMAN, WALT
    - Clippings, notes, offprint portrait WW newsletter, 1950-56, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3935)
  - WOOLF, VIRGINIA
    - Clippings, notes, ca. 1941-56, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3936)
    - Lecture notes (?), 1951-52, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3937)
  - YEATS, WILLIAM BUTLER
    - Clippings, notes, 1951-58, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3938)
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - Clipping, n.d. (Box 395, Folder 3939)
- Photographs, 1900-88; Series VII; 11.34; (29 boxes)
  Series VII, Photographs, consists of
  ten subseries, which are arranged
  alphabetically and chronologically.
  - GLENWAY WESCOTT
    - Photographic portraits
      - Abbé, James, Sr., 1925-26 (Box 396, Folder 3940-3942)
        One shot in Marguerite Namara's
        apartment in Paris
      - Adams, Ansel, ca. 1940s-50s
      - Caskey, William, 1947 (Box 396, Folder 3943)
      - Caron, Charles, 1952 Jan 29 (Box 396, Folder 3944)
      - Ciavolino, M., 1958
      - Deane, Peter, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3945)
      - Francos, J. B., n.d.
      - Goldberg, Maurice, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3946)
      - Krementz, Jill, 1976 May 19 (Box 396, Folder 3947)
      - Lansdale, Nelson, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3948)
      - Lynes, George Platt, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3949-3950)
      - Miller, Art, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3951)
        With letter from Hazel Herman
      - Miller, Christian William, 1951, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3952)
      - Schreiber Studio, ca. 1919 (Box 396, Folder 3953)
      - Silbert, Layle, 1978 (Box 396, Folder 3954)
      - Stevenson, John, 1983
      - Tichenor, Jonathan, 1945 Jan (Box 396, Folder 3955)
      - Tuttle, Irv, 1966 Aug 30 (Box 396, Folder 3956)
      - Ulmann, Doris, 19[21?]-ca. 1929 (Box 396, Folder 3956a)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3957-3958)
    - Photographs of artists' portraits of GW
      - Portraits by Don Bachardy, Paul Cadmus, Jean Cocteau, Olga Sorenson, Bernard Perlin and Pavel Tchelitchew, 1925-45 (Box 396, Folder 3959)
    - With other people
      - Bowen, [Elizabeth?] at National Book Awards Banquet, 1950 Mar 16 (Box 396, Folder 3960)
      - Butler, Earl, 1978, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3961)
      - Chandlee, Will, and Bill Bewick and MW, 1977 Sep (Box 396, Folder 3962)
      - Connolly, John and Ivan Ashby and MW (Box 396, Folder 3963)
      - Evans, Helen P., 1928 (Box 396, Folder 3964)
      - Fiedler, Leslie at University of Utah Writers' Conference, 1956 Jun 17 (Box 396, Folder 3965)
      - Hagen, Beulah at Harpers' 150th Anniversary party, 1967 Jan 25 (Box 396, Folder 3966)
      - Kinsey, Alfred in Bloomington, Indiana, 1951 Jul 18 (Box 396, Folder 3967)
      - Klein, Cord, 1977 (Box 396, Folder 3968)
      - Lansdale, Nelson and Rosemary Marrow, ca. 1941 (Box 396, Folder 3969)
      - Maugham, W. Somerset, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3970-3971)
        One shot by S. Balkin
      - Melton, Fred, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3972)
      - Moore, Marianne, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3973)
      - Moore, Marianne, at MacDowell Colony, n.d.
        By Jerry Berkery
      - Mosher, Arthur and children on board S. S. Argentina, 1952 Jun-Jul (Box 396, Folder 3974)
      - Mortimer, Raymond (Box 396, Folder 3975)
      - Nugent, Elliott and others (including MW) (Box 396, Folder 3976)
      - Pohorilenko, Anatole, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3977)
      - Pomeroy, Ralph, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3978)
      - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1960, 1968 (Box 396, Folder 3979)
        Several shots are of the dedication
        of the KAP Room at the University of
        Maryland, 1968
      - Porter, Katherine Anne, at publisher's party for Ship of Fools, 1962 Apr 2
        By Paul Berg
      - Prockup, Jennifer, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3980)
      - Rothschild, Baron Philippe de [with Stephen Spender?] (Box 396, Folder 3981)
      - Searle, Alan, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3982)
      - Stevenson, John, 1974, 1979 (Box 396, Folder 3983)
        One shot by Jill Krementz
      - Wescott, Barbara, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3984)
      - Wescott, Josephine, 1958
        By M. Ciavolino
      - Wescott, Lloyd, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3985)
      - Williams, Tennessee and MW, 1975 May 15 (Box 396, Folder 3986)
        By Gerard Malanga
      - Wescott family, 1976, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3987)
      - Wescott, Josephine, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3988)
      - Wilder, Thornton, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3989)
      - Unidentified, ca. 1918-80 (Box 396, Folder 3990-3991)
    - Candids
      - GW at Falling Water, n.d. (Box 396, Folder 3992)
      - GW in Mrs. Mastrangel's garden, 1951 (Box 396, Folder 3993)
      - GW at Felicia Geffen's by Harold Strauss, 1962 Jul 14 (Box 396, Folder 3994)
      - GW at Hay Meadows, ca. 1960-64 (Box 396, Folder 3995-3996)
      - GW "when Buddie M. and Gil Anderson were at St.-bl.", ca. 1954 Sep 12 (Box 396, Folder 3997)
      - General candids, ca. 1910-87 (Box 397, Folder 3998-4001)
      - Set of copy prints of GW and others, [possibly for Continual Lessons ?], ca. 1920-87 (Box 397, Folder 4002)
        [From the collection of Lloyd
        Wescott?]
        Includes: GW, MW, GPL, Barbara
        Wescott, Lloyd Wescott, Thornton
        Wilder, Marianne Moore, Christian
        William Miller, Jean Cocteau, E. M.
        Forster, Fred Danieli, and cast of
        "Invitation to Learning"
      - Empty photo sleeves, annotated, 1963, 1982
  - MONROE WHEELER
    - Photographic portraits
      - Abbé, James, Sr., 1925 (Box 398, Folder 4003)
      - Adams, Ansel, n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4004)
      - Blackstone Studios, n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4005)
        Publicity photo for MOMA
      - Bouton, Alfredo, in Caracas, Venezuela, 1972 (Box 398, Folder 4006)
      - Carmine, A., n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4007)
      - Cooke, Jerry, n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4008)
      - Delbo, P., n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4009)
      - Dellenback, n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4010)
      - Dykes, Melvin H., n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4011-4012)
        Includes shot of MW in military uniform
      - Francos, J. B., n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4013)
      - Howard, Charles, n.d. (Box 398, Folder 4014)
      - Lynes, George Platt, ca. 1928-55 (Box 398, Folder 4015-4027)
      - Lynes, George Platt: Album of MW
        Photographs from album, retained in
        original order
        - Page 1, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4028)
        - Page 2, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4029)
        - Page 3, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4030)
        - Page 4, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4031)
        - Page 5, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4032)
        - Page 6, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4033)
        - Page 7, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4034)
        - Page 8, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4035)
        - Page 9, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4036)
        - Page 10, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4037)
        - Page 11, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4038)
        - Page 12, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4039)
        - Page 13, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4040)
        - Page 14, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4041)
        - Page 15, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4042)
        - Page 16, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4043)
        - Page 17, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4044)
        - Page 18, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4045)
        - Page 19, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4046)
        - Page 20, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4047)
        - Page 21, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4048)
        - Page 22, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4049)
        - Page 23, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4050)
        - Page 24, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4051)
        - Page 25, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4052)
        - Page 26, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4053)
        - Page 27, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4054)
      - New York Times Studio, 1967 Apr 21 (Box 399, Folder 4055)
      - Ray, Eugene L., n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4056)
      - Roehle, E., 1921, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4057-4058)
      - Schafgans, Theo, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4059)
      - Stevenson, John, 1979 (Box 399, Folder 4060)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 399, Folder 4061-4063)
    - Photographs of artists' portraits of MW
      - Cadmus, Paul, 1937-39, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4064)
      - Cocteau, Jean, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4065)
      - Perlin, Bernard, 1949, 1965 (Box 400, Folder 4066)
      - Sterne, Hedda, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4067)
      - Tchelitchew, Pavel, ca. 1935-45 (Box 400, Folder 4068)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4069)
    - With other people
      - Anderson, Clinton P. at AIGA (Box 400, Folder 4070)
      - Astor, Brooke, 1971, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4071)
      - Burke, Kenneth, by Harold Strauss, ca. 1970s (Box 400, Folder 4072)
      - Butts, Mary, in Villefranche, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4073)
      - Cadmus, Paul, and Jon Andersson, 1970, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4074)
      - Cocteau, Jean, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4075)
      - Cottenet, R. L., 1926 Oct (Box 400, Folder 4076)
      - Curtius, Ilse, 1932 Jan (Box 400, Folder 4077)
      - Edwards, Malu, and Windy Larsen in Chile (Box 400, Folder 4078)
      - Fairfax, James, 1976 Jul (Box 400, Folder 4079)
      - Hochschild, Walter (Box 400, Folder 4080)
      - Knollys, Eardley, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4081)
      - Kolbe, Marjorie Heartt, 1974 (Box 400, Folder 4082)
      - Krimpen, Jan van, and Gerard Proost and Barbara Wescott, ca. 1931 (Box 400, Folder 4083)
      - Lawson, Kate, ca. 1928 (Box 400, Folder 4084)
      - Lynes, George Platt, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4085)
      - MacLeish, Archibald, 1936 May (Box 400, Folder 4086)
      - Martinson, Burt, in Acapulco, 1938 (Box 400, Folder 4087)
      - Maugham, W. Somerset, 1946, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4088)
      - Miller, Christian William, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4089)
      - Montgomery, George, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4090)
      - Mortimer, Raymond, 1965, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4091)
      - Pevsner, Antoine, 1950 (Box 400, Folder 4092)
      - Pohorilenko, Anatole, ca. 1971-73 (Box 400, Folder 4093)
      - Pomeroy, Ralph, 1951, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4094)
      - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1962, 1980, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4095)
        Includes shot of party at "21" for Ship of Fools with Eleanor Clark,
        Robert Penn Warren, Oscar Williams,
        and Mark Schorer
      - Prockup, Jennifer, 1982 (Box 400, Folder 4096)
      - Reynolds, Mary, ca. 1929 (Box 400, Folder 4097)
      - Richardson, Harry, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4098)
      - Rodgers, Richard, Mrs., 1948
        By Serge Balkin for Vogue or Harper's Bazaar
      - Rogers, Agnes, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4099)
      - Searle, Alan, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4100)
      - Simpson, Kelly, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4101)
      - [Soutter, Paul?], ca. 1927 (Box 400, Folder 4102)
      - Thayer, Jeanne and P. McCray (Box 400, Folder 4103)
      - Vorse, Mary Ellen, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4104)
      - Weil, Hope, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4105)
      - Wescott, Barbara, 1931, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4106)
      - Wescott, Lloyd, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4107)
      - Wheeler, Richard, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4108)
      - Wheeler family, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4109)
      - Wilder, Thornton, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4109a)
      - Wimmer, Kurt and Ighino, ca. 1927 (Box 400, Folder 4110)
      - Wojtasik, Ted, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4111)
      - Yeon, John, n.d. (Box 400, Folder 4112)
      - Caretakers, 1987 (Box 400, Folder 4113)
      - Unidentified, ca. 1925-85 (Box 400, Folder 4114-4115)
    - Candids
      - Age 2, 1901 Jun 3 (Box 401, Folder 4116)
      - Age 4, 1903 Mar (Box 401, Folder 4117)
      - Age 11, ca. 1910 (Box 401, Folder 4118)
      - On terrace of La Cabane, 1928 May (Box 401, Folder 4119)
      - In Evanston, Illinois, 1918 (Box 401, Folder 4120)
      - At Flemington Hospital, 1987 May (Box 401, Folder 4121)
      - In train near Villefranche-sur-Mer, France, ca. 1926 (Box 401, Folder 4122)
      - In garden, 1953 (Box 401, Folder 4123)
      - At Hay Meadows, 1971 (Box 401, Folder 4124)
      - In Barbara Wescott's Hispano-Suiza, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 4125)
      - "Last photos ever taken of MW", ca. 1987-88 (Box 401, Folder 4126)
      - In Cuautla, Mexico, 1940 (Box 401, Folder 4127)
      - [In Oaxaco, Mexico?], 1953 (Box 401, Folder 4128)
      - At desk at Museum of Modern Art, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 4129)
      - [At Museum of Modern Art?], n.d. (Box 401, Folder 4130)
      - At opening of Monroe Wheeler Reading Room, Museum of Modern Art, 1988 (Box 401, Folder 4131)
      - "Newark Evening News photograph; intended to illustrate Elizabeth McFadden's interview", 1966 Aug (Box 401, Folder 4132)
      - At 251 East 51st Street, New York City (Box 401, Folder 4133)
      - Passport photo, ca. 1921 (Box 401, Folder 4134)
      - Passport photo, 1951 May (Box 401, Folder 4135)
      - Passport photo, 1961 Sep (Box 401, Folder 4136)
      - Passport photos, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 4137)
      - With his Peugeot, ca. 1926 (Box 401, Folder 4138)
      - At Katherine Anne Porter's, 1974 Jan (Box 401, Folder 4139)
      - Scrapbook, ca. 1900-45
        Includes shots of MW at various
        ages and artists' portraits by Paul
        Cadmus, Jared French, and Pavel
        Tchelitchew
      - At Skowhegan Awards ceremony for Kenneth Clark, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 4140)
      - Deboarding plane, Malaga, Spain, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 4141)
      - Nude series at Stone Blossom, n.d. (Box 401, Folder 4142)
      - At Stone Blossom, 1952 (Box 401, Folder 4143)
      - At Stone Blossom, 1953 Aug (Box 401, Folder 4144)
      - At Stone Blossom, 1955 (Box 401, Folder 4145)
      - "The weekend at St.-Bl. with CWM and WSM after J. Tichenor's leaving GPL", [1943] (Box 401, Folder 4146)
      - On bicycle in St. Moritz, Switzerland (Box 401, Folder 4147)
      - General candids, ca. 1910s-30s (Box 401, Folder 4148-4158)
      - General candids, ca. 1940s-80s (Box 402, Folder 4159-4167)
  - GLENWAY WESCOTT AND MONROE WHEELER
    - Candids, ca. 1920s-80s (Box 402, Folder 4168-4169)
    - Scrapbook, ca. 1910s-20s (Box 402, Folder 4170)
      Includes: shots of Sante Fe,
      New Mexico, ca. 1920, with Yvor
      Winters and one shot of Elly Ney
  - OTHER PEOPLE
    - Aguilar, Mauricio, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4171)
    - Ames, Louis, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4172)
    - Auric, Georges, ca. 1927 (Box 403, Folder 4173)
    - Baldwin, Billy, n.d.
    - Barr, Alfred, 1935 Aug (Box 403, Folder 4174)
    - [Bianco?], Margery Williams, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4175)
    - Bissinger, Scott, 1950 Aug 4 (Box 403, Folder 4176)
    - Bogan, Louise, 1961 (Box 403, Folder 4177)
    - Braake, Anna, 1966 Mar 27 (Box 403, Folder 4178)
    - Brasseur, Jean-Pierre, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4179)
    - Brinkerhoff, Nelson, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4180)
    - Brinser, Fritz, and Gretchen Walds (Box 403, Folder 4181)
    - Brook, Hugh, [1928 Jun] (Box 403, Folder 4182)
    - Buchanec, Martin and Justina, 1959 Jan (Box 403, Folder 4183)
    - Bull, Wesson, n.d.
    - Butts, Mary, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4184)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1940 (Box 403, Folder 4185)
    - Cadmus, Paul, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4186)
    - Cannon, Glenn, 1983 (Box 403, Folder 4187)
    - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, ca. 1943 (Box 403, Folder 4188)
    - Cobb, Eliza Bliss Parkinson, n.d.
      By John Stevenson
    - Cocteau, Jean, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4189)
    - Colette, 1951, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4190)
    - Connolly, John, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4191)
    - Covarrubias, Rose, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4192)
    - Cromwell, Dick
    - Daniels, Jimmy
    - Desbordes, Jean, ca. 1927 (Box 403, Folder 4193)
    - de Souza, Dr., [from Davos], n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4194)
    - Doro, Marie, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4195)
    - Dudley, Kathleen, mother of, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4196)
    - Ferreira, Francisco, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4197)
    - Forbes, Don, 1946 Feb (Box 403, Folder 4198)
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1932
      By Katherine Anne Porter
    - Forster, E. M., n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4199)
    - French, Jared, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4200)
    - Fritz, Chester, and "Anna May" (Box 403, Folder 4201)
    - Gaffney, Jack Daniel, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4202)
    - Genet, Jean, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4203)
    - Gill, Cecil and Colin Hope, 1942 (Box 403, Folder 4204)
    - Gillum, Jack Larsen, [1951? Nov 27] (Box 403, Folder 4205)
    - Goff, Lloyd, 1939 Nov (Box 403, Folder 4206)
    - Goodspeed, Bobsy, 1949 May (Box 403, Folder 4207)
    - Goyen, William, 1974 Mar 7 (Box 403, Folder 4208)
    - Hallacy, David, 1964 Jul (Box 403, Folder 4209)
    - Halliday, Mary, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4210)
    - Hammond, Anne and May, 1954 (Box 403, Folder 4211)
    - Hatfield, Ted and Anne (Box 403, Folder 4212)
    - Heard, Richard, 1960, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4213)
    - Herbert, David with Cecil Beaton, 1947 Apr (Box 403, Folder 4214)
    - Humphrey, Paul, 1918 (Box 403, Folder 4215)
    - Isherwood, Christopher, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4216)
      Photo by William Caskey
    - Jacobs, Alethea Austin, 1979-83 (Box 403, Folder 4217)
    - Jacobs, Bill, and wife, 1978 Sep 2 (Box 403, Folder 4218)
    - Jacobs, Katharine and Henry, 1963 (Box 403, Folder 4219)
    - James, Edwards, 1948 Feb (Box 403, Folder 4220)
    - Johnson, Philip, ca. 1950 (Box 403, Folder 4221)
    - Kauffman, Herbert H., n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4222)
    - Kent, Henry Watson, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4223)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, with José Martinez, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4224)
    - Knollys, Eardley, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4225)
    - Kolbe, Frank and Marjorie (Box 403, Folder 4226)
    - Kuelthau, Earl Rix, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4227)
    - Lansdale, Henry Nelson, ca. 1938, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4228)
    - Lawson, Kate Drain, 1963, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4229)
    - Leavitt, David, 1949, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4230)
    - Leavitt, Paul, 1937 (Box 403, Folder 4231)
    - Levy, Joella [with Wesson Bull?], n.d.
      On verso: Hans Namuth
    - Lightheart, Norman F., 1918 (Box 403, Folder 4232)
    - Lynes, George Platt, ca. 1925-55 (Box 403, Folder 4233-4239)
      Includes shots by George
      Hoyningen-Huene, and one by Douglas
      Baz of GPL with nephew, George Platt
      Lynes II
    - Lynes, Russell, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4240)
    - McAndrew, John (Box 403, Folder 4241)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset, n.d. (Box 403, Folder 4242)
      Includes photos by S. Balkin,
      Douglas Black, and Fred Lyon
      Alan Searle is in several shots
    - Maxon, Glenway, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4243)
    - Melton, Fred, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4244)
    - Melville, Grevis, 1944-45, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4245)
    - Miksche, Michael, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4246)
    - Miller, Christian William, ca. 1945-60 (Box 404, Folder 4247-4255)
    - Montgomery, George ["Geordie"], 1949-51, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4256)
    - Moore, Marianne, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4257)
      Includes copyprint of photo by
      Cecil Beaton
    - Moore, Marianne, in Brooklyn antique shop, ca. 1963
      By Esther Bubley
    - Moore, Marianne, with her bust by Gaston Lachaise, 1963
    - Moore, Marianne, with her mother at 260 Cumberland Street, Brooklyn
      By Cecil Beaton
    - Namuth, Hans
      See: Levy, Joella, Box 478, folder 5335
    - Moore, Mary Warner, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4258)
    - Mortimer, Raymond (Box 404, Folder 4259)
    - Namara, Marguerite, ca. 1920 (Box 404, Folder 4260)
    - Ney, Elly, 1932, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4261-4262)
    - Nyquist, Frederick, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4263)
      Includes shot with Richard Wheeler
    - O'Higgins, Patrick, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4264)
    - Pelaez, Amelia, with mother and sisters (Box 404, Folder 4265)
      By George Moffett
    - Perlin, Bernard, ca. 1944, 1949 (Box 404, Folder 4266)
    - Peterson, Donald and Eric, 1946 Sep (Box 404, Folder 4267)
    - Picasso, Pablo, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4268)
      This photo is #15 in a series of 24 taken in a single day by Jean Cocteau. It documents an outing by Picasso and several of his friends, including Max Jacob and Modigliani.
    - Platt, George, n.d. (Box 404, Folder 4269)
      [Great-uncle of George Platt Lynes]
    - Pohorilenko, Anatole, ca. 1972-84 (Box 405, Folder 4270-4271)
    - Pomeroy, Ralph, 1955-64, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 4272)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, ca. 1925-67 (Box 405, Folder 4273-4274)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, ca. 1950s
      By Arthur Long
    - Porter, Katherine Anne posed at typewriter, 1950 or 1958
    - Rain, Charles, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 4275)
    - Renault, Jean-Marie, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 4276)
    - Robbins, Frances C. Lamont, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 4277)
    - Rothschild, Pauline de, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 4278)
    - Sansone, Anthony, ca. 1928 (Box 405, Folder 4279)
      Standing by statue by Arthur Lee
    - Saportas, Marion Tiffany, n.d.
      By [Fonsagrives?]
    - Searle, Alan, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 4280)
    - [Selwart?], Tonio, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 4281)
    - Sforza, Sforzano, with André de Mandiargues, Cesare Pavani, and Stanislao Lepri, 1949 (Box 405, Folder 4282)
    - Sibelius, Jean, 1935 (Box 405, Folder 4283)
      By H. Iffland
    - Sitwell, Edith, n.d. (Box 405, Folder 4284)